Aaron Craig's CV

Contact Info Email: aaroncraig@protonmail.ch

20D Portland Crescent Website: github.com/craigthelinguist Thorndon, Wellington

SKILLS

Programming Languages: Java, C, Python, Prolog, Haskell, SQL

Modelling Languages: Alloy, UML, LTSA, Isabelle Markup Languages: Latex, Markdown, JSON, XML

Libraries & Frameworks: JUnit, pandas, matplotlib, numpy, curses, OpenGL, XStream, Berkeley

Socket API, Swing, Unity Protocols: HTTP, DNS

Job History

Victoria University, Wellington

Research Assistant

Oct 2015 - Current

- Contributed to the Wyvern interpreter: github.com/wyvernlang/wyvern
- Developed a type system for effect inference in record calculi.
- My supervisors are Alex Potanin and Jonathan Aldrich.

New Zealand Registry Services, Wellington

Research Intern

Oct 2014 - Current

- Analysis and summary of DNS data with pandas, matplotlib.
- Detection and classification of botnet domains using clustering techniques.
- Gather, verify, analyse routing data for generating maps of NZ internet.
- Natural language processing on domain names.

Victoria University, Wellington

Sessional Assistant & Tutor

Mar 2014 - Oct 2015

- Marking tests and assignments; invigilating.
- Running tutorials, labs, and helpdesks.
- Classes tutored: Intro to Computer Science; Engineering Modelling & Design; Data Structures & Algorithms II; Formal Foundations of Programming.

Converga Ltd., Petone

Business Processing Clerk

Nov 2013 - Mar 2014

- Data entry and verification.
- Sorting files by hand. (I did this using radix sort)

Target Furniture, Porirua

Temp, Storeperson

Nov 2010 - May 2013

- Furniture removal, delivery, assembly, and repair.
- Managing inventory, driving forklift.
- Training temps.
- Greeting and assisting customers.

Interests & Projects

Natural Language Processing. One of my dreams is to develop and improve algorithms for recognising and producing human language. I have made several corpora for Māori and NZ English. At NZRS I looked at detecting botnet activity in DNS by classifying domain names. As part of that I gave a presentation at the 2015 NZ Internet Research Forum.

Programming Languages. Exploring the space of formal languages helps shed light on the mysteries of natural languages. Furthermore, the role of language in software development is critically underappreciated. I want to develop expressive, safe ways for programmers to write software. I'm a contributor to the Wyvern project and especially interested in type systems and static analysis.

Visualisations. At NZRS I helped verify data used to generate a map of the NZ internet. I've written several interactive visualisations for algorithms (A*, Kruskal's Knight's Tour, KNN), cellular automata, and Turing machines. These are all much easier to explain in pictures than in words or mathematical formalism, which can be cumbersome and unintuitive.

Education. I would like to see NZ education offer more in the way of computer science and logic for high school students and would be excited to work towards such goals. I like the idea of using history-themed games to convey the geopolitics of an era.

Game Development. Each year I attend Pixeljam, a 48hr gamejam in Wellington. Over the years we've made several flavours of game such as: a lane-runner, a Mario-style platformer, and a 3d horror game.

EDUCATION

Victoria University of Wellington, New Zealand

	•	O	/
•	STAR Programme		

• BA Linguistics & Philosophy 2012

BSc Computer Science & Mathematics
BSc Hons. Computer Science
2013 - Current
2016 - Current

Tawa College, New Zealand

• NCEA Level 3 (Merit endorsement)

2011

2011

Scholarships & Awards

Victoria University of Wellington

Victoria Achievers Scholarship
Dean's List
Zurrent

Tawa College

• Katherine Mansfield Award (English)	2011
• Leanne Dixon Cup (History)	2011
NZQA Outstanding English Scholarship	2011

LANGUAGES

English

Māori (Elementary)

ABOUT ME

I was born in Porirua and live in Wellington. I like creative writing and reading history, philosophy, and fiction. For two years I boxed as an amateur but nowadays just like to watch. My tribe is Muaūpoko, in Horowhenua.

References

Available upon request.